<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="css/document.css"?>
<document>
	<header>
		<title>Toska Quick Start</title>
		<subtitle>Toolkit for OpenSsh key Administration</subtitle>
		<authors>
			<person name="Gianugo Rabellino" email="gianugo@apache.org"/>
		</authors>
	</header>
	<body>
	<section title="A quick start guide">
	 <p>
   OK, I will write more documents, promise, but as of now this is
   a quick start that should be enough to have you up and running in
   minutes.
   </p>
	 <section title="Prerequisites">
   <p>
   A Java Virtual Machine, 1.3 or later (yes, it works with 1.4 too),
   nothing else, no database, no LDAP: the data are kept on disk in a 
   pure XML format.
   </p>
   </section>
	 <section title="Start up">
   <p>
   If you have Java Web Start installed, all you need to do is point
   your browser 
   <link href="http://toska.sourceforge.net/webstart/toska.jnlp">here</link>.
   I experienced some weird connection timeouts with Sourceforge, but I
   hope it was just me. If this is not the case, please drop me a note.
   </p>
   <p>
   If you don't have Java Web Start you can download the sotware (binaries
   or source). All you have to do (after compilation if you downloaded the
   sources) is to launch the run(.sh|.bat) script.
   </p>
   </section>
	 <section title="The main screen">
   <p>
   Once started, the main screen shows up. The main part, as you will soon
   notice, is the tree on the left side. From there you can right-click on
   the nodes and a contextual menu will allow you to operate on the data 
   model, adding and removing keys/hosts/users, enabling or disabling keys,
   </p>
   <figure src="images/toska-main.png" alt="Toska main screen"/>
   <p>
   Should any user input be required, a panel will appear in the right side
   of the application, allowing you to fill the required informations.
   </p>
   <figure src="images/toska-addkey.png" alt="New SSH key"/>
   <p>
   The previous image, by the way, shows you a populated tree. It's worth
   noticing that one of the keys (the one with gianugo@rabellino.it) is
   disabled (in grey). That key won't be included once the data will be
   deployed.
   </p>
   <p>
   Also, note how every operation is logged on the status window. This 
   allows you to understand what is the program doing.
   </p>
   </section>
	 <section title="Once you're done...">
   <p>
   The first thing you have to do is save your data. The "Save" menu is there
   to help you: it will save an XML file containing your setup (this, by the
   way, means that you can edit it by hand if you're not that much into GUIs).
   </p>
   <p>
   But in the end what you want is to upload the keys to the servers. To do 
   this choose the "Deploy to filesystem" menu entry. Once you have chosen 
   a directory, the program will start dumping your data there, and you will
   find a set of directories named as per your hosts. Under every host 
   directory you will find a file, named as per your users, in the OpenSSH 
   authorized_keys format. All you have to do is to "scp" those files to 
   your machines (yes, a script is underway, be patient :-)).
   </p>
   </section>
  </section> 
	</body>
</document>
